Guide to the New Deal in Montana/Fort Peck Dam Oral History Project 1987-1989
Montana Historical Society Research Center
- HERBERT JACOBSON INTERVIEW, OH 1107; 1 tape(s), Transcript 28 pages
  Herbert Jacobson (b. 1913) discusses growing up in Fairview, North Dakota, and Lambert, Montana; loss of family homestead during the Great Depression; working for the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), including camp discipline and organization, work as a carpenter in the Alder, Paradise, and Thompson Falls areas, fire fighting at Elk Lake, and road and trail construction work; Fort Peck dam; education at Montana State College, Bozeman; service in U.S. Navy during World War II; predator and wildlife control; health care; and his views on Franklin Roosevelt, Adolph Hitler, Joseph Stalin, Communism, and the Anaconda Company. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- JOE KNUTSON INTERVIEW, OH 1108; 1 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Joe Knutson was a Civilian Conservation Corps worker in West Yellowstone, Montana in the late 1930s. He remembers building roads, camp life, social activities, and equipment used. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- EDMOND B. CHERRY, JR., INTERVIEW, OH 1109; 2 tape(s), Summary 6 pages
  Edmond Cherry, Jr. (b. 1916), was a Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) worker in Montana in the 1930s. He discusses traveling during the depression, life in the CCC camps, fighting fires, social activities in Dillon, camp leaders. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 9 & 10, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- MILTON RITTER INTERVIEW, OH 1110; 2 tape(s), Summary 17 pages
  Milton Ritter worked for the Civilian Conservation Corps in Glacier National Park, Montana during the 1930s. Ritter discusses Depression conditions; his work building campgrounds; surveying for a telephone line; fighting fires; camp life; a visit by President Franklin D. Roosevelt; military service. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- HAROLD SHREWSBERRY INTERVIEW, OH 1111; 1 tape(s), Summary 3 pages
  Harold Shrewsberry (b. 1918) discusses his service in the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) in the Libby, Montana area during the 1930s including a discussion of camp life, cooking for the camp, wages, equipment, social activities. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- GLEN MOORE INTERVIEW, OH 1112; 1 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Glen Moore (b. 1912) discusses his service in the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) in the late 1930s; including his work at the Kerr Dam, St. Regis road construction, camp life, and his work on a Utah bird refuge. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- LARRY NORRIS INTERVIEW, OH 1113; 1 tape(s), Summary 2 pages
  Larry Norris (b. 1914) discusses working for the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) in Paradise and Moiese, Montana and in California; including fire fighting, work as camp clerk, morale in the camps. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT
- KNUTE KAMPEN INTERVIEW, OH 1114; 1 tape(s), Summary 3 pages
  Knute Kampen (b. 1916) served in the Civilian Conservation Corps from 1937-1938 at Medicine Lake, Squaw Creek, and Thompson Falls, Montana. He discusses his work at a bird refuge, on a rock crew, building trails, camp life. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- ROBERT HALLIDAY INTERVIEW, OH 1115; 1 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Robert Halliday, a Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) worker in the 1930s, discusses depression conditions, a strike in CCC camp, recreation, relations with Dillon, Montana towns people, work as head of a maintenance crew and wages. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- KENNETH GILLESPIE INTERVIEW, OH 1116; 1 tape(s), Summary 2 pages
  Kenneth Gillespie discusses his work for the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) in Havre and Fort Missoula, Montana in the 1930s; setting up the post exchange system for the Fort Missoula district; and his military career. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 26, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- JESS STOVALL INTERVIEW, OH 1117; 1 tape(s), Summary 7 pages
  Jess Stovall (b. 1910) discusses her work for the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) in the Yellowstone National Park area during the 1930s; Depression conditions; camp life; social activities; and men in the camp. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- RALPH BOATMAN INTERVIEW, OH 1118; 1 tape(s), Summary 5 pages
  Ralph Boatman (b. 1914) was a Civilian Conservation Corps worker in Utah and Idaho in the 1930s. He discusses road construction, different camps, work accidents. Interviewed by Michael Korn, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- ALBERT TONG INTERVIEW, OH 1119; 1 tape(s), Summary 11 pages
  Albert Tong (b. 1915) describes his early childhood in Montana; his experiences in the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) at Camp Nine Mile, Goat Creek, and Belton; daily life at the camps; and his motorcycle. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- HAROLD DUCELLO INTERVIEW, OH 1120; 1 tape(s), Summary 12 pages
  Harold Ducello discusses his experiences in the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) near Ekalaka and Augusta, Montana. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- STUART MARKLE INTERVIEW, OH 1121; 1 tape(s), Summary 6 pages
  Stuart Markle (b. 1916) discusses his experiences in the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) at Clam Lake near Glidden, Wisconsin; and World War II service as a crew member of a navy sea plane bomber operating in Ecuador and the Galapagos Islands. Interviewed by Mike Korn, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- ARTHUR MORANG INTERVIEW, OH 1122; 2 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Arthur Morang discusses his experiences with the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) in Nine Mile, Montana; areas outside Missoula; Moab, Utah; and his later life. Interviewed by Mike Korn, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- ARTHUR CHARKOFF INTERVIEW, OH 1123; 1 tape(s), Summary 7 pages
  Arthur Charkoff (b. c. 1917) discusses his parents immigration from Russia and settlement in Montana; his service in the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), stationed at Camp F76 near Libby; reactions of local people to CCC workers; his duties in the camp infirmary; service in Army Air Force in Europe during World War II; college education and work following military service. Interviewed by Mike Korn, July 9, 1988, Dillon, MT.
- TOM COLLERAN INTERVIEW, OH 1124; 1 tape(s), Summary 3 pages
  Tom Colleran (1898-1994) was a Montana Relief Commission worker in Jordan and Baker, Montana from 1934 until 1948. He discusses his job as a caseworker, the process of applying for relief, clients, types of relief. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 23, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- MARY BRADY INTERVIEW, OH 1125; 1 tape(s), Summary 15 pages
  Mary Brady (1910-2001) discusses her employment in the Miles City, Montana Works Progress Administration (WPA) office from 1935 to 1938; and brief employment with the Civil Works Administration. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 19, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- JOE W. LOVEC INTERVIEW, OH 1126; 1 tape(s), Summary 20 pages
  Joe W. Lovec (b. 1915) discusses his early life on a homestead near Baker, Montana; experiences with the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), 1934-1935, at camps near Whitetail and Volborg, Montana; describes camp construction, camp life, recreation, and discipline; opinions of New Deal; life in eastern Montana during the Depression; sheep and cattle ranching in Fallon and Custer counties. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 21, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- JEAN STANLEY INTERVIEW, OH 1127; 1 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Jean Stanley describes growing up near Ismay, Montana; working in Works Progress Administration (WPA) sewing room; her father's WPA work; living conditions during the Depression; and the New Deal. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 20, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- ELLA AND ELLIOT MILLER INTERVIEW, OH 1128; 2 tape(s), Summary 14 pages
  Elliot Miller discusses his parents' covered wagon journey from South Dakota to Montana; homesteading; experiences with the National Youth Administration (NYA) at Fort Keogh, Montana, including horse breeding and frozen semen studies conducted by Dr. Stuart McKenzie; attending Montana State College; ranching; and poetry. Ella Miller discusses her parents' immigration from Ireland; her mother's death; her marriage to Elliot Miller; raising a family; experiences with the NYA; athletics; coping with insects; and ranching. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 22, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- DAVID RIVENES INTERVIEW, OH 1129; 2 tape(s), Summary 9 pages
  David Rivenes, a Miles City, Montana resident discusses his work with the U.S. Department of Agriculture during the Depression of the 1930s, the government's Land Utilization Program, the Soil Conservation Service, agricultural practices, drought, dryland farming, grazing districts. Rivenes also discusses running his TV station and amateur athletic activities including Taekwondo and Sumo wrestling. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 20, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- C. MAX HUGHES INTERVIEW, OH 1130; 1 tape(s), Summary 7 pages
  C. Max Hughes discusses his parents homestead in the Roundup area; college education; the Kinsey Project; recollections of the Works Progress Administration (WPA); the Land Utilization Project and dam construction in eastern Montana; Soil Conservation Service; and Depression of 1930s. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, July 21, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- JEROME COOKSEY INTERVIEW, OH 1131; 2 tape(s), Summary 13 pages
  Jerome Cooksey discusses his work with the Agriculture Survey in Custer County, Montana, during the 1930s; various New Deal Programs; the economic Depression of 1930s; his experiences with Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) and his employment with the local cannery and Montana/Dakota Utility. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, August 5, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- JOSEPH DENT INTERVIEW, OH 1132; 3 tape(s), Summary 14 pages
  Joseph Dent (1902-1994) discusses his work for the Works Progress Administration (WPA) in Broadus, Lame Deer and Forsyth, Montana as a foreman and finance officer in construction, timbering, surveying and road work. He also discusses community activities such as playing the piano for local dances. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, August 6, 1988, Broadus, MT.
- CECIL E. WYNES INTERVIEW, OH 1133; 2 tape(s), Summary 9 pages
  Cecil E. Wynes (1910-2000) discusses his parents' homestead; his experiences during the 1930s Depression; working with the Works Progress Administration (WPA) in the Miles City and Glendive areas; his military service; employment as an automobile mechanic; and his retirement. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, August 8, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- GEORGE GRAY INTERVIEW, OH 1134; 2 tape(s), Summary 11 pages
  George Gray discusses his experiences with the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) at Camp 967, Glacier National Park; the camp's organization, entertainment activities, and army administrators; winter living conditions; deserters; the installation of telephone cable under Going-to-the-Sun Highway; and later life. Interviewed by Doni Phillips, August 8, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- DONALD MORROW AND AGNES MORROW INTERVIEW, OH 1135; 2 tape(s), Summary 17 pages
  Don Morrow (b. 1916) discusses growing up in Mildred and Glasgow; his marriage to Agnes Wagner; his family's work during the construction of Fort Peck Dam; President Franklin Roosevelt's visit to the dam; memories of Wheeler, Montana; his relocation to Harlem; experiences during building of the Snake Butte Dam; and health care. Agnes Morrow discusses her memories of the construction of Fort Peck Dam; the 1930s Depression; work women did in the Fort Peck area; and family life. Interviewed by Laurie Mercier, August 15, 1988, Helena, MT.
- JOHN MORRISON, SR. INTERVIEW, OH 1136; 3 tape(s), Transcript 38 pages
  John Morrison (b. 1902) discusses his childhood in England; his immigration to Montana in 1922; his work on the Bozeman Hill Road and the Mosby bridge; depression conditions of the 1930s; the Works Progress Administration (WPA); and his work as a Montana Highway Department engineer including construction standards and materials. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 7, 1988, Helena, MT.
- ETHEL E. GEORGE INTERVIEW, OH 1137; 1 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Ethel George (b. 1903) discusses her childhood in the Midwest; raising a family during the economic depression of the 1930s; family life and health care; farming and ranching in the Miles City area; relocation to Kinsey as part of the Resettlement Administration program; 1943 flood and other recollections. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 18, 1988, Kinsey, MT.
- MADELINE O'NEILL INTERVIEW, OH 1138; 1 tape(s), Summary 3 pages
  Madeline O'Neill (1912-1990) describes her work as a nurse in Bozeman and Helena, Montana from the 1930s to the 1960s including discussions of diseases; lack of antibiotics; the nurses' relationship with physicians. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 11, 1988, Bozeman, MT.
- CHARLOTTE EDWARDS INTERVIEW, OH 1139; 2 tape(s), Transcript 30 pages
  Charlotte Edwards (b. 1913) discusses her youth and schooling in Custer and Powder River Counties; working with the Agricultural Adjustment Administration in Powder River County; depression conditions; working for the Custer County Treasurer's office. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 14, 1988, Helena, MT.
- ELIZABETH PHELPS INTERVIEW, OH 1140; 2 tape(s), Transcript 36 pages
  Elizabeth Phelps (b. 1923), a Sidney, Montana resident remembers her childhood in the 1930s; the Depression; her mother's work for a Works Progress Administration (WPA) nursery school; local social activities; living conditions; farm activities; National Youth Administration projects. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 16, 1988, Sidney, MT.
- HELEN MATHIASON AND RENO ESKRO INTERVIEW, OH 1141; 1 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Helen Mathiason (b. 1921) and Reno Eskro (b. 1912), residents of Mildred, Montana discuss their work with the National Youth Administration; projects of the Works Progress Administration (WPA); the Depression of the 1930s; work of relatives for the Milwaukee Railroad. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 17, 1988, Mildred, MT.
- KENTON STICKNEY INTERVIEW, OH 1142; 1 tape(s), Summary 3 pages
  Kenton Stickney (b. 1911) describes the depression of the 1930s in the Ismay, Montana area; ranching; social activities; Works Progress Administration (WPA) work. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 17, 1988, Ismay, MT.
- MARY A. BALLENTINE INTERVIEW, OH 1143; 2 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Mary Ballentine (1901-1996) a Miles City, Montana resident, discusses growing up, schooling, social activities, marriage, and her family. She also discusses her husband's work for the Works Progress Administration as a welding instructor and the depression conditions of the 1930s. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 17, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- FRED L. CAMPBELL, SR. INTERVIEW, OH 1144; 1 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Fred Campbell (1912-1989) a Kinsey, Montana resident, discusses his schooling; depression conditions of the 1930s; working for the Works Progress Administration building dams, surveying, farming; social activities. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 18, 1988, Kinsey, MT.
- HENRY CHRISTMAN AND LYDIA CHRISTMAN INTERVIEWS, OH 1145; 1 tape(s), Summary 3 pages
  Henry Christman (1911-1994) and Lydia Christman, Plevna, Montana residents discuss depression conditions of the 1930s; working for the Work Progress Administration moving buildings; social activities; their children. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 18, 1988, Plevna, MT.
- BERDETTE ASKIN INTERVIEW, OH 1146; 1 tape(s), Summary 2 pages
  Berdette Askin (1907-1993) an Ismay and Terry, Montana resident, discusses his schooling; work digging wells; work for Works Progress Administration in the Kinsey area; Depression conditions of the 1930s. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 17, 1988, Ismay, MT.
- JOHN WILLMAN AND MONTE RENE WILLMAN INTERVIEW, OH 1147; 1 tape(s), Summary 8 pages
  John Willman (1902-1995) and Monte Willman discuss their childhoods; the depression conditions of the 1930s; work for the Works Progress Administration (WPA) and National Youth Administration (NYA); social activities in Plevna, Montana; and Cheyenne Indians in the Lame Deer area. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 17, 1988, Plevna, MT.
- FRED ROSLER AND MARTHA ROSLER INTERVIEW, OH 1148; 1 tape(s), Summary 2 pages
  Plevna, Montana residents Fred Rosler and Martha Rosler (b. 1899) discuss the Depression conditions of the 1930s, work for the Works Progress Administration (WPA), farm life, and drought. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 17, 1988, Plevna, MT.
- LAWRENCE HAMAN AND LILY HAMAN INTERVIEW, OH 1149; 1 tape(s), Summary 7 pages
  Lawrence and Lily Haman (1912-1991), Miles City, Montana residents discuss depression conditions of the 1930s; their work for the Works Progress Administration; ranching; droughts; and social activities. Interviewed by John Terreo, November 18, 1988, Miles City, MT.
- KENNETH J. TURNER INTERVIEW, OH 1150; 2 tape(s), Summary 12 pages
  Kenneth Turner (b. 1914) discusses growing up on a homestead near Great Falls, Montana; the depression of the 1930s, including work in gold and coal mines; the Rural Electrification Administration (REA); the Resettlement Administration of the Farmers Home Administration (FHA); the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC); the Works Progress Administration (WPA); and bootlegging during Prohibition. Interviewed by John Terreo, Nov. 22, 1988, Kremlin, Mont.
- LEO REMSH INTERVIEW, OH 1151; 2 tape(s), Summary 12 pages
  Leo Remsh (b. 1914) discusses his childhood and education in Great Falls, Montana; experiences during the Great Depression; his work with the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) during early 1930s at Apgar, Montana and Moab, Utah; and his later life in Great Falls. Interviewed by John Terreo, December 1, 1988, Great Falls, MT.
- JULIA JUNE CHITWOOD TREES INTERVIEW, OH 1152; 2 tape(s), Transcript 58 pages
  Julia Trees (b. 1920) a resident of Fishtail, Montana discusses her family life and growing up in Carbon County during the Great Depression, including her mother working in a Works Progress Administration (WPA) sewing room; her experiences with the National Youth Administration (NYA); and her career as a teacher. Interviewed by John Terreo, December 13, 1988, Fishtail, MT.
- HENRY JORGENSEN INTERVIEW, OH 1153; 2 tape(s), Transcript 33 pages
  Henry Jorgensen (b. 1912) talks of his family and homestead in the area of Dagmar, Montana; business and agriculture in Sheridan County, Montana; the formation of Sheridan County; the 1930s Depression; the construction of the Fort Peck Dam; his experiences with the Works Progress Administration Historical Records Survey Project; work as principal at Central High School in Helena; memories of C.R. Anderson; teaching and public education. Interviewed by John Terreo, January 31, 1989, Helena, MT.
- BESSIE HEJLESEN INTERVIEW, OH 1154; 1 tape(s), Summary 6 pages
  Bessie Hejlesen discusses her early life and family; relocation to Montana in covered wagon; the family homestead; raising a family; and recollections of the 1930s depression. Interviewed by John Terreo, February 15, 1989, Helena, MT.
- GRANT MEYERS INTERVIEW, OH 1155; 2 tape(s), Transcript 34 pages
  Grant Meyers discusses road construction in Western Montana during the 1930s including MacDonald Pass, Lolo Hot Springs, Libby, Elliston, and Helena; types of horse-drawn equipment and paving materials; and general living and working conditions for construction and survey crews. Interviewed by John Terreo, February 15, 1989, Helena, MT.
- GEORGE BROOKS AND NEVA BROOKS INTERVIEW, OH 1156; 2 tape(s), Transcript 28 pages
  George Brooks (1902-1990) discusses his early life and family in Livingston, Montana; work as a printer for the Livingston Enterprise and Independent Record; and the 1930s Depression. Neva Brooks (1908-1997) discusses her early life and family; attitudes toward women during 1920s and 1930s; employment as a telephone operator; the 1930s Depression; work with the Montana legislature during the 1950s; and her retirement. Interviewed by John Terreo, February 16, 1989, Helena, MT.
- DORIS GRIBBLE INTERVIEW, OH 1157; 2 tape(s), Transcript 36 pages
  Doris Gribble (1908-1991) discusses her early childhood in Alysworth, Oklahoma; relocation to Montana in 1916; attending school in Lewistown, Montana; raising a family and life in Great Falls during the Great Depression; her husband's work with the Works Progress Administration (WPA); work as a Licensed Practical Nurse (LPN) in Great Falls and Townsend, Montana; the licensing of LPNs in Montana; and changes in nursing since the late 1940s. Interviewed by John Terreo, February 28, 1989, Helena, MT.
- CLARICE THOMAS INTERVIEW, OH 1158; 2 tape(s), Summary 4 pages
  Clarice Thomas discusses her children and family; experiences as a ranch wife in Montana before and during the 1930s Depression; Franklin Roosevelt's welfare programs, including the Works Progress Administration (WPA) the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) and the Production Credit Association (PCA); her home at Shawmut, Montana; making and selling apple box furniture; social activities; women's role in health care; living without electricity; drought; welfarism; and Christianity. Interviewed by John Terreo, March 14, 1989, Townsend, MT.
- MARGARET DAVIS INTERVIEW, OH 1159; 2 tape(s), Summary 14 pages
  Margaret Davis (1889-1995) discusses her childhood; her parent's homestead near Blossburg, Montana; her own homestead; starting a family; the 1930s Depression; seeing her first airplane; getting electricity and road construction; the 1935 earthquake in Helena; relocating to Helena; World War I; World War II; and health care in rural areas. Interviewed by John Terreo, April 19, 1989, Helena, MT.
- MARK LAROWE INTERVIEW, OH 1160; 2 tape(s), Transcript 51 pages
  Mark LaRowe (b. 1915) discusses his work with the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) in California and in Haugan, Montana during the late 1930s including living conditions, work as camp cook, social activities; his naval service in the Pacific during World War II; and his operation of a motel in Circle, Montana. Interviewed by John Terreo, May 19, 1989, Roberts, MT.
- MARY LAROWE INTERVIEW, OH 1161; 1 tape(s), Summary 10 pages
  Mary LaRowe (b. 1918) discusses her parents and growing up on a homestead near Glendive; marriage; family; opinions on New Deal programs. Interviewed by John Terreo, May 19, 1989, Roberts, MT.
- MAE TAKES GUN CHILDS INTERVIEW, OH 1162; 1 tape(s), Transcript in-process pages
  Mae Takes Gun Childs (b. 1892), daughter of Dessie Bad Bear, compares Crow Agency Superintendents Ashberry and Yellowtail; the first Sundance on Crow Agency; Crow Fair celebrations; attending the Mission School (Urseline Sisters); peyote use and police attempts to limit it; and CCC camps. Interviewed by Carson Walks Over Ice, May 10, 1989, Crow Agency, MT.
- EFFIE HOGAN INTERVIEW, OH 1163; 1 tape(s), Transcript 10 pages
  Effie Hogan discusses her recollections of Ashberry, the Superintendent of Schools on the Crow Reservation; Superintendent Robbie Yellowtail (Effie's husband); the Shoshone Sundance; Caleb Bull Shows, William Big Day, Camel Big Hail, Henry Big Day (dancers in the Sundance); Crowfair celebrations; and the construction of roundhalls. Interviewed by Carson Walks Over Ice, May 22, 1989, Little Big Horn National Battlefield, Crow Agency, MT.
- THOMAS BULL-OVER-HILL INTERVIEW, OH 1164; 1 tape(s), Transcript 9 pages